<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Professional | ryan straight, ph.d</title>
    <link>https://ryanstraight.com/category/professional/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ryanstraight.com/category/professional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Professional</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 06:27:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ryanstraight.com/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Professional</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/category/professional/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/project/cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 06:27:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/project/cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yup, I&amp;rsquo;m heading back to school in the spirit of lifelong learning and professional development. This is all my website content that revolves around that: cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to School</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/back-to-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/back-to-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2015, when I walked across the stage in the Convocation center on the main Ohio University campus in Athens, OH, and was hooded by my inimitable advisor, it occurred to me that I&amp;rsquo;d never be a student again. I&amp;rsquo;d be teaching, sure&amp;ndash;heck, I was already a program director at that point&amp;ndash;but I&amp;rsquo;d likely never get that feeling again of being on &lt;em&gt;that side&lt;/em&gt; of the lectern, as it were. Excited for new ideas and topics and discussions and, let&amp;rsquo;s face it, deadlines. You never quite realize how much you miss having a clear roadmap of what to do provided to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward five years. I&amp;rsquo;m still a program director, still teaching in that same college, but things have changed a bit. Namely, the SARS-CoV2 pandemic. From a logistical standpoint, at least in our house, not much has changed aside from my wife now working from home for the foreseeable future. The dogs are loving that and it means I get to spend more time with her, even if that&amp;rsquo;s mostly peeking around corners to make sure she&amp;rsquo;s not on a Zoom call when I walk past. I&amp;rsquo;m still teaching from my home office/studio, still tweaking my presentation format and style, still dialing in the audio settings and lighting. Still teaching HCI and game design and statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float: right;&#34; src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/RHKIKFgCC9WKqh4b0J/giphy.gif&#34;&gt;But the way COVID-19 has washed over the country and ravaged the higher education system has brought a few things into a stark light. Namely, that for contingent faculty (not just adjunct but those of us that are on yearly contracts and are not tenured or tenure-track) there is potentially great peril ahead through no fault of your own. If the tides turn and your area becomes less viable and appealing to incoming students, you may just find yourself out of a job, even if you&amp;rsquo;re tenured. Higher education isn&amp;rsquo;t alone in this, of course, and I do commend my home department and college for doing what they can to make sure we&amp;rsquo;re not as impacted on the personnel side as other units may be, but the constant threat, however real or not, is worrying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to go back to school and get another Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Cybersecurity. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been interested in a variety of sub-topics therein, from forensics to the philosophical side of how we live online, globally speaking. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to it and I&amp;rsquo;m assured I will have fun. (Truth be told, I&amp;rsquo;ve no doubt about that; I&amp;rsquo;ve always thoroughly enjoyed being a student and it will be nice to remind myself just what it&amp;rsquo;s like and thereby even improve my own teaching as a result.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;If you hate change, you’re really going to hate being irrelevant” &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cyborgoddess?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@cyborgoddess&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SNHU?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@snhu&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/EntangledSOL?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@EntangledSOL&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#39;s Town Hall today. Bam. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/PpZgc4O8zH&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/PpZgc4O8zH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jenny Herrera (@mrsjennyherrera) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mrsjennyherrera/status/1255917194912960514?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;April 30, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to document the process here as, like with open source software, I believe in transparency of experience to bring us all together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be learning 
  &lt;i class=&#34;fab fa-python  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Python from scratch as I go forward. I&amp;rsquo;ve already started down that road to an extent but I doubt I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing any of that kind of content/work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still teaching a 4/4 load, still our college&amp;rsquo;s Faculty Forum president, still doing all the things I have to do as a full-time faculty member at a college that values teaching excellence and student experience. Obviously, the priority in terms of work is my job, my classes, then updating this. So, things may come in fits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I firmly believe in being a life-long learner (&amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; or otherwise) and highly encourage those working in places that pay for continuing education to absolutely take advantage of that at every turn. If you can take a college class for $25 because your employer covers the tuition and fees, you should be doing it if at all feasible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to see proof that a professor can still struggle, well, buckle in. I imagine I&amp;rsquo;ll trip and fall a few times over the next year-and-a-bit while I finish this degree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to join me on this little journey if you like. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying what comes of it will be as useful or impactful as, say, the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raulpacheco.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;academic strategies of Dr. Raul Pacheco-Vega&lt;/a&gt; but I&amp;rsquo;ll hope for some good to come of it, at least. If me sharing my experience helps anybody, I&amp;rsquo;ll consider it a double-win.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicing Up Your Remote Work with Zoom and OBS</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/zoom-and-obs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/zoom-and-obs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: Using virtual cams broke in Zoom past version 4.6.7. Bummer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE 2&lt;/strong&gt;: Works again! Who knows how long it&amp;rsquo;ll stay that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems like everybody I know is now working remotely due to the virtual worldwide lockdown in the face of the COVID-19 pandemic. Lots of folks that have little to no experience with it. And that&amp;rsquo;s okay! We&amp;rsquo;re all in this together. At this point, simple ettiquite and knowing how to mute your microphone should be considered passable skills. I shared a couple Twitter threads about teaching online but wanted to do something more tutorial-ish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; comfortable with working remotely and want to do something a bit more interesting than just, &amp;ldquo;Hey, look! I&amp;rsquo;m in a desert now!&amp;rdquo; well, this is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/20k1punZ5bpmM/source.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Travolta in front of a green screen&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-youll-need&#34;&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;ll need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presuming you already have a webcam and a microphone, this is all free. (Yay, right?) Here&amp;rsquo;s the list of extra software you&amp;rsquo;ll need to make this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OBS Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. That&amp;rsquo;s the list. Okay, you need the &lt;em&gt;VirtualCam&lt;/em&gt; plugin, but whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-obs-studio&#34;&gt;What is OBS Studio?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OBS stands for &lt;em&gt;Open Broadcaster Software&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the ways in which streamers do what they do. It&amp;rsquo;s free, open source, and not the most user friendly thing, so&amp;hellip; you take the good with the bad. Luckily, for our purposes, we don&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything all that crazy. (That&amp;rsquo;s another post in the future.) We&amp;rsquo;re using OBS &lt;em&gt;Studio&lt;/em&gt; because it&amp;rsquo;s the best for this situation for a few different reasons that I needn&amp;rsquo;t go into here, really. Just trust me on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, install OBS Studio and head into its Preferences to make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve got your settings configured properly. I&amp;rsquo;d suggest choosing either 1080 or 720 for your resolution. If you&amp;rsquo;re using Zoom, while your live stream in the meeting may be in HD, any recording of it is likely set to be SD, so keep that in mind for later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-the-virtualcam-plugin&#34;&gt;Install the VirtualCam plugin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what makes the magic work. Head over to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/forum/resources/obs-virtualcam.539/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the OBS forum for instructions on how to download and install the VirtualCam plugin&lt;/a&gt; for OBS. Use the &lt;em&gt;Go to download&lt;/em&gt; button on the top right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, go do it. I&amp;rsquo;ll wait. (You can choose just the single camera install option. I chose the 4 cameras but have never used more than one, so&amp;hellip;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-virtualcam-do&#34;&gt;What does VirtualCam do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, &lt;em&gt;VirtualCam&lt;/em&gt; takes your OBS output and turns it into a virtual camera that your meeting software can choose as a video input. Basically, instead of Zoom (for example) using your webcam, you can now use OBS. What does that mean? Well this is where it gets fun. Follow the instructions on the plugin page to get it going in OBS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beginner-add-a-logo&#34;&gt;Beginner: Add a logo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple way to see what OBS can do for you here is just to add a logo to your webcam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just find the image you want (when using Google Image Search or whatever your preferred engine is, make sure to search for &lt;em&gt;Transparent&lt;/em&gt; images so your logo doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a big solid background).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s get our first scene set up. Add your audio and video sources (microphone and webcam, respectively). Stretch the webcam source out to match the OBS canvas. Check your microphone to make sure the levels are active in the source monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great, now at this point if we went into Zoom and switched the video source to &lt;em&gt;VirtualCam&lt;/em&gt;, it would just be identical to what you&amp;rsquo;d normally see. You only have your webcam and microphone running. But that&amp;rsquo;s not why we&amp;rsquo;re here, is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Down in your sources, where you added your webcam and your microphone, add an &lt;em&gt;Image&lt;/em&gt; source. Find the transparent logo you downloaded and select that. Next, resize and move that puppy around on the screen to wherever you want it. Voila, you now have a logo on your webcam in Zoom!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;block-a.png&#34; alt=&#34;Webcam feed with Arizona block A on left, &amp;ldquo;stand by&amp;rdquo; scene on right.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty easy, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intermediate-add-a-brb-screen&#34;&gt;Intermediate: Add a BRB screen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say you need to go away from the keyboard for a bit. Bathroom, feed the dogs, get coffee, whatever. Normally, in Zoom, you&amp;rsquo;d just turn off your video and audio. But why do that when we can have a bit more fun with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I put on the screen when I leave for a minute: &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/3o7TKDsHWoAbGkcTEk/source.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Coffee BRB gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s how to do it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Head on over to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Giphy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the thing you want to use for your BRB screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on &lt;em&gt;Media&lt;/em&gt; and copy the MP4 link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Head on over to that URL, right click on the video, and &lt;em&gt;Save video as&lt;/em&gt; to whatever folder you want to keep this stuff in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open up OBS and create a new scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For your source, add a Media Source or VLC Video Source (either works)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose that video file you downloaded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stretch it out to fill or fit the canvas, whichever you want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it! You&amp;rsquo;re done! Just remember you also need to still mute yourself in your meeting software as this is &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; a video source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switching to and from your scenes is easy and the Studio Mode in OBS Studio makes it pretty visually pleasing, as well. Simply hit the &lt;em&gt;Transition&lt;/em&gt; button in the middle of Studio Mode interface and it&amp;rsquo;ll switch what&amp;rsquo;s in the &lt;em&gt;Preview&lt;/em&gt; scene (left) to be what&amp;rsquo;s sent to the &lt;em&gt;Program&lt;/em&gt; you&amp;rsquo;re using (right). (That&amp;rsquo;s what shows up in Zoom.) Like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;obs-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;OBS Studio screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-multiple-screen-elements&#34;&gt;Advanced: Multiple screen elements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check back in the future for a rundown on how I use OBS Studio in my online classes to include on-screen elements like scrolling due dates, realtime key-presses to support coding demonstrations, adding a cropped version of my camera feed over a slide deck, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just scratching the surface in terms of how this method of virtual presence can ramp up engagement in online classes but hopefully this post gives you everything you need to start playing with OBS Studio and (for example) Zoom to spice up what&amp;rsquo;s likely to be a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of online meetings!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you end up doing something you think is really neat, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ryanstraight&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tweet at me&lt;/a&gt; and let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re having difficulties with the sources, check out 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/obsproject/obs-studio/wiki/Sources-Guide#vlc-video-source&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the GitHub documentation&lt;/a&gt; for explanations. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picking the Low-Hanging Fruit of Privacy and Security</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little while back I was involved in a Twitter thread in which I suggested the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Brave browser&lt;/a&gt; for its integrated privacy and security settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Both! I sync my Brave wallet across all my browsers, though. This is just one of the browsers and, wow, it&amp;#39;s disturbing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/aziApUdiQA&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/aziApUdiQA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dr. Ryan Straight&amp;#39;s Still Staying Home Aren&amp;#39;t You? (@RyanStraight) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/RyanStraight/status/1201891797011763200?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 3, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s fairly striking, I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Maybe I should do a blog post on this kinda thing. A &amp;quot;so you want to be safer in 2020&amp;quot; kinda thing with some low-hanging fruit (like switching from Chrome to Brave).&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dr. Ryan Straight&amp;#39;s Still Staying Home Aren&amp;#39;t You? (@RyanStraight) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/RyanStraight/status/1201892630109528064?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 3, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here it is: my &amp;ldquo;So You Want To Be Safer In 2020&amp;rdquo; post! I&amp;rsquo;ll preface it with this: this is &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; opinion based on the products and services I know. Does it mean this is 100% the best way to go about it or there aren&amp;rsquo;t potentially better options out there? Not at all. But if you want to hear firsthand experience, you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-you-mean-low-hanging-fruit&#34;&gt;What do you mean, &amp;ldquo;low-hanging fruit?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the topics I address pretty heavily in my classes is the importance of finding a balance between usability and security. As the old joke goes, &amp;ldquo;The most secure system is one you can&amp;rsquo;t access.&amp;rdquo; This isn&amp;rsquo;t what I&amp;rsquo;m addressing here today but it does lead us down this road: what are the simple solutions you can choose that will have the least impact on your day-to-day user experience? Some of these are simpler than others but I think everything below is definitely worth looking into. Note that I&amp;rsquo;m not affiliated with any of these products or services, though you may find the occasional affiliate link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now. First things first:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;internet-traffic-generally-get-yourself-a-vpn&#34;&gt;Internet traffic, generally: get yourself a VPN&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard the term before. VPN stands for &lt;strong&gt;V&lt;/strong&gt;irtual &lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;rivate &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;etwork. The way it works is basically like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;VPN_explained_transparent_grey.png&#34; alt=&#34;VPN Monitor EU&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A VPN creates an encrypted (read: secure) line between you and the internet. Traffic from your computer goes through the VPN before it gets anywhere else and vice versa. This protects you from, among other things, snooping by your internet service provider (ISP), tracking/identification by the websites you visit, and unwanted incoming connections. It also anonymizes you to the rest of the world (within reason; if you sign into a website that will give the game away, of course) and allows you to get around government or other blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-this-low-hanging-fruit&#34;&gt;Why is this low-hanging fruit?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of its relative simplicity to use. It looks and sounds complicated but these days it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as signing up for the service, installing the app, and &amp;hellip; well, that&amp;rsquo;s about it. Most commercial VPNs will run perfectly fine just out of the box, though you can tweak some settings (like where you &lt;em&gt;look&lt;/em&gt; like you&amp;rsquo;re geographically located and whether or not you want X app or Y app to bypass the VPN connection &amp;ndash; handy for Netflix since they block most proxies/VPNs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-pick-private-internet-accesshttpsamznto2yvkbtb&#34;&gt;My pick: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2YvkbtB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Private Internet Access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re cheap, fast, and work on virtually any device. You can purchase any number of service lengths (monthly, annually, etc.) on their website or just get a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2YvkbtB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;one-year subscription here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-tracking-and-ads-change-your-browser--search-engine&#34;&gt;Web tracking and ads: change your browser &amp;amp; search engine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of our online lives are lived in web browsers and social media apps, it seems (and we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to the latter in a bit). That said, it only stands to reason that your online experience is only as good as your browser. Chrome currently stands as the browser king with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usage_share_of_web_browsers#Summary_tables&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;roughly 65% of the browser market share&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-this-low-hanging-fruit-1&#34;&gt;Why is this low-hanging fruit?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly because of my pick for an alternate browser. It&amp;rsquo;s the same experience but with increased security and privacy. And that is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-picks-bravehttpswwwbravecom-and-duckduckgohttpduckduckgocom&#34;&gt;My picks: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brave.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Brave&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://duckduckgo.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, Brave is actually a version of Chrome. Anything you can do in Chrome, you can do in Brave. It&amp;rsquo;s actually built on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howtogeek.com/202825/what%E2%80%99s-the-difference-between-chromium-and-chrome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chromium, the open-source platform that makes Chrome possible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brave has built-in ad blocking and privacy controls. When these features are enabled, Brave refers to it as being &lt;em&gt;shields up&lt;/em&gt; (though it does break some websites, so switching to &lt;em&gt;shields down&lt;/em&gt; is occasionally necessary but it&amp;rsquo;ll be obvious when that&amp;rsquo;s the case). Here&amp;rsquo;s what happens if you visit, say, Buzzfeed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;brave-shields.png&#34; alt=&#34;Brave shields on Buzzfeed&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s not even nearly the worst perpetrator I can think of, it was just a random popular website that came to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also the whole Brave Rewards program and a built-in version of cryptocurrency called the Basic Attention Token (BAT) that can be used to tip websites that have enabled it but that&amp;rsquo;s another post. Feel free to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/tips/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;throw a tip my way&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re using it, though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the search engine, just moving away from Google is a huge step (because nobody actually uses Bing, let&amp;rsquo;s be honest). My typical go-to for search engines is 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://duckduckgo.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt; (which, ironically, &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; use Bing&amp;rsquo;s results along with many, many others). It&amp;rsquo;s easy to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.brave.com/hc/en-us/articles/360017479752-How-do-I-set-my-default-search-engine-&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;switch your default browser search engine in Brave&lt;/a&gt; and their private windows (like Incognito in Chrome) uses it automatically. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in using Google&amp;rsquo;s results, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.startpage.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;you can try StartPage&lt;/a&gt;, instead, which is also a great choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;credentials-use-a-password-vault-and-2fa&#34;&gt;Credentials: use a password vault and 2FA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot emphasize this enough: use long, unique passwords for everything and enable two-factor authentication everywhere you can. Let&amp;rsquo;s have a little thought experiment, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve been using the same email and password for everything for years. Let&amp;rsquo;s say it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;password1&lt;/code&gt;. (Think that&amp;rsquo;s too obvious? It doesn&amp;rsquo;t even 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.welivesecurity.com/2018/12/17/most-popular-passwords-2018-revealed/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;crack the top 20&lt;/a&gt; of the most popular passwords.) So you&amp;rsquo;ve been using that password everywhere from your university email to Netflix to the bank to a silly little website you don&amp;rsquo;t even remember signing into a couple years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it likely your university or your bank or Netflix is going to find their entire user database of credentials obtained and leaked? Nah, probably not. That&amp;rsquo;s not how these things typically go. What will usually happen is that little website you signed up for (and probably even forgot about) gets hacked and, because they didn&amp;rsquo;t know what they were doing, kept all their users&amp;rsquo; emails and passwords in plain text right there on the server. (Sound unlikely? 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2019/03/facebook-stored-hundreds-of-millions-of-user-passwords-in-plain-text-for-years/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s what Facebook did for years&lt;/a&gt;.) So while your email and bank and Netflix weren&amp;rsquo;t hacked, someone&amp;ndash;and, likely, anyone who wants to search the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;half-billion passwords&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed online&amp;ndash;now has those credentials because they&amp;rsquo;re the same everywhere. So, all that person has to do in theory is take that email and password combination, start visiting popular websites, and eventually they&amp;rsquo;re going to get lucky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is a true nightmare just waiting to happen. That particular nightmare could&amp;rsquo;ve been avoided by just using different passwords for everything. But who wants to keep track of all those, right? Well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-this-low-hanging-fruit-2&#34;&gt;Why is this low-hanging fruit?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because services like the ones I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen for my picks are so dead simple to use that the tiny learning curve is absolutely justified by the benefits of using the services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-picks-lastpasshttpslastpasscom-and-authyhttpsauthycom&#34;&gt;My picks: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://authy.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Authy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both are both browser extensions and stand-alone phone apps. LastPass keeps track of all those passwords for you, even updates automatically when you need or decide to change your password. It can generate passwords as long and as complex as you need. It even provides what they call the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://helpdesk.lastpass.com/lastpass-security-challenge/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Security Challenge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that audits your entire collection of usernames and passwords and tells you if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) any are duplicates and used on more than one site,&lt;br&gt;
b) if any of your passwords are just generally weak,&lt;br&gt;
c) if any of your email addresses are included in lists of exposed credentials online,&lt;br&gt;
d) if any of your passwords are old, and&lt;br&gt;
e) how you compare to the rest of the LastPass community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take an afternoon and get it set up. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s the two-factor authentication (2FA). Know when you&amp;rsquo;re prompted to put in a 6-digit code after signing into a website? That&amp;rsquo;s that. While many just use the &amp;ldquo;send me an SMS&amp;rdquo; option (terrible, by the way), you can improve upon that with an app that has multi-device support. My favorite is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://authy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Authy&lt;/a&gt;, which is hands-down better 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://authy.com/blog/authy-vs-google-authenticator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;than the other most popular one, Google Authenticator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chatting-switch-your-chat-app&#34;&gt;Chatting: switch your chat app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text messages are inherently insecure. WhatsApp is owned by Facebook. Signal is secure but it still uses your phone number. Telegram isn&amp;rsquo;t open source. Allo is owned by Google. Skype is owned by Microsoft. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.securemessagingapps.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The list goes on&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to be sure that your communications are secure and you&amp;rsquo;re talking to whomever they &lt;em&gt;say&lt;/em&gt; they actually are, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a different option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-this-low-hanging-fruit-3&#34;&gt;Why is this low-hanging fruit?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implications for privacy, more or less. Right up there with your passwords and protecting your internet traffic, this is no less important so the stakes are much higher. After all: would you be okay with someone listening in on your phone calls? That feels oddly more invasive, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t feel exactly as invasive as someone potentially reading your chats. Heck, that&amp;rsquo;s even worse because you can just print out the transcript and &lt;em&gt;voila&lt;/em&gt;. In short, there&amp;rsquo;s a record. If you can convince anyone of doing anything, this&amp;ndash;changing the means of communication you use&amp;ndash;is a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-pick-keybasehttpskeybaseio&#34;&gt;My pick: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Keybase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? Well, in short:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;width:100%;height:0;padding-bottom:70%;position:relative;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://giphy.com/embed/e7yNPQmGUozyU&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; style=&#34;position:absolute&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;giphy-embed&#34; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://giphy.com/gifs/facebook-posts-privacy-e7yNPQmGUozyU&#34;&gt;via GIPHY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keybase was originally just a new place to generate and keep PGP keys (tl;dr: a way to securely message people that nobody ever really, actually uses in the real world). They&amp;rsquo;ve been expanding and expanding since those days and now they provide chat, teams (like Slack or group messaging), secure file storage, cryptocurrency wallets, and even encrypted Git repositories (a way of storing and change-tracking code, more or less). Since their platform is open source, it&amp;rsquo;s inherently more secure since anyone can look at and improve the code. Combine that with the fact content from Keybase users is end-to-end encrypted (like what happens in the VPN, more or less), the Keybase folks can&amp;rsquo;t even actually see what you&amp;rsquo;re saying or what your files are or &amp;hellip; well, anything. They can see a message was sent, what time it was, that sort of thing (known as &lt;em&gt;metadata&lt;/em&gt;) but the content of that stuff? Totally secure (insofar as you don&amp;rsquo;t lose your device; they have no control over you being a doofus).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find me at &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/ryanstraight&#34;&gt;https://keybase.io/ryanstraight&lt;/a&gt; if you want to give it a trial run and say hi. 😁 I&amp;rsquo;ll also say I&amp;rsquo;m not affiliated with Keybase in any way or do they sponsor or give me anything. I just really like their product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We switched from WhatsApp to Keybase a while ago for our daily communication and I can say it&amp;rsquo;s been pretty painless. In Keybase you can still share a live location, you can share gifs, leave voice messages instead of typing, everything you can do with other chat platforms, you can do in there. There are some really nice other features, too, like easy access to all the files and links you&amp;rsquo;ve shared back and forth. One killer feature I&amp;rsquo;d love to see, though, is like how Signal can be used as both a secure messaging app (if both people use Signal) or a default SMS app (if you get a text from someone &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; on Signal, it still shows up &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; Signal). I&amp;rsquo;d love if Keybase could do the same thing. Likewise, a direct &amp;ldquo;Send to Keybase user&amp;rdquo; in the system share dialog would be great and save a few steps (compared to copying and pasting URLs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and if you want to leave a message that&amp;rsquo;ll disappear after a set length of time, you can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/blog/keybase-exploding-messages&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;do that, too&lt;/a&gt;. 💣&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/download&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Getting set up on Keybase&lt;/a&gt; can be a &lt;em&gt;tad&lt;/em&gt; confusing if you&amp;rsquo;re thinking it&amp;rsquo;s just a chat app because, as I said, it&amp;rsquo;s much more than that. The benefits are so great, though, that I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to just get whomever you also want to switch set up (if necessary, just do it for them) as once you&amp;rsquo;re up and running the experience is incredibly familiar. Especially if you&amp;rsquo;re coming from WhatsApp for Facebook Messenger&amp;hellip; because my next thing is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-media-deletefacebook&#34;&gt;Social media: #DeleteFacebook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t make an entire post about security and privacy online without mentioning #DeleteFacebook, right? This one really is a bit of a no-brainer, although I&amp;rsquo;m on the fence about whether it&amp;rsquo;s actually low-hanging fruit. For a lot of people, Facebook is how they stay in contact with family, friends, communities, and perhaps even conduct business. For some, it&amp;rsquo;s their living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-this-low-hanging-fruit-4&#34;&gt;Why is this low-hanging fruit?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure it is for a large portion of the population. I just think it&amp;rsquo;s important enough to include, regardless. Also, I&amp;rsquo;ll say this: after leaving Facebook, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself considerably more positive and compassionate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;It occurs to me that my tweets over the past few weeks have become markedly more positive and supportive, rather than critical and complaintive. I wonder if it has to do with me leaving Facebook. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/DeleteFACEBOOK?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#DeleteFACEBOOK&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/PTyAO8V6pS&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/PTyAO8V6pS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Dr. Ryan Straight&amp;#39;s Still Staying Home Aren&amp;#39;t You? (@RyanStraight) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/RyanStraight/status/1199331737567973379?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;November 26, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-pick-thats-complicated&#34;&gt;My pick: that&amp;rsquo;s complicated&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, there really is no viable alternative to Facebook. Not really. There are networks out there that are &lt;em&gt;trying&lt;/em&gt; (Peepeth comes to mind but the blockchain integration, while good in theory, is just too overly complicated for widespread adoption, at least right now) and some that are so focused on anti-censorship that they turn into magnets for alt-right hate, but none that even come close to being as ubiquitous and entangled with our daily lives (for better or worse).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, you have something really promising like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.okuna.io/en/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Okuna&lt;/a&gt;, which is still in private beta but is open source and focused on respecting user privacy. Looking forward to getting in there. Christmas present, perhaps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Okuna&amp;rsquo;s not gotten the funding it had hoped to get recently so it&amp;rsquo;s unclear if it will ever actually come to fruition. Worse comes to worse, you can always stand up your own Mastodon or just invite your friends to Keybase and start a Team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I&amp;rsquo;m still 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ryanstraight&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; but have moved mostly away from using Instagram. Nobody&amp;rsquo;s perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, there you have it: five relatively simple, small changes you can make in your daily online lifestyle that will reap &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; benefits. Even doing just one of these things will be an improvement. I hope this has been useful!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Order in Chaos</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2018-11-02-finding-order-in-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2018-11-02-finding-order-in-chaos/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://ryanstraight.com/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to say I’m the &lt;em&gt;typical&lt;/em&gt; professor (heck, I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenewprofessor.com&#34;&gt;an entire podcast devoted to exploring just what the heck that means&lt;/a&gt;) but I certainly do occasionally resemble the clichéd &lt;em&gt;absent-minded professor&lt;/em&gt;. Remember: good thoughts are clear thoughts and that’s much harder than it sounds when your job is to think about so much, so often, for so long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it simply, we have a lot of stuff in our heads. In my experience, one of the most difficult and daunting aspects of working in a primarily intellectual field is nothing more than the organization of thoughts and ideas. We’re confronted with new ideas, questions, corrections, updates, improvements, alterations, and retractions nearly every day as we learn more and more about virtually everything. So the question becomes: if we’re not superhuman, how do we keep track?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose you could make it your priority to spend the entirety of your time and energy on memorizing the minutiae of everything but, let’s face it, we’re not all cut out for that kind of perfect recall. I, for one, need to keep notes or I just &lt;em&gt;forget&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe you’re the same. But then the question becomes: where do you keep them? How do you organize them? How much do you automate and how much do you update? Whether it’s your reading notes on one particular scholar’s &lt;em&gt;ouvre&lt;/em&gt; or a little reminder to add a particular resource to an assignment for a class, we (normally) can’t just keep all that in our heads. I know some people, like the prolific Raul Pacheco-Vega, that use physical bucket-style collections (in his case, the “Everything Notebook”). Others create hundreds or thousands of Google Documents or giant Scrivener projects. The important part is that it works &lt;em&gt;for them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a very, very long time to figure out a system that a) is sustainable, b) I’ll actually use, and c) is designed in a way that mirrors (or at least generally reflects) the way my thought processes work. I tried virtually every organizational paradigm out there, from the Evernote-style bucket to physical notebooks (and, I have to say, I’m devastated that physical notebooks don’t do it for me because I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; them and own many, many blank ones). What I discovered is, beyond all that, that I love creating systems. What I love less than that is &lt;em&gt;maintaining&lt;/em&gt; them. So, my job became to find a system that I felt like I was creating &lt;em&gt;all the time&lt;/em&gt;, something malleable, something always growing and improving, and something within which I could automate the more mundane tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve listened to &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenewprofessor.com/019/&#34;&gt;episode 19 of The New Professor&lt;/a&gt;, you already know what I’m going to say next: for me, even though it may sound like a lot of work, the best environment to off-load information and ideas is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.semantic-mediawiki.org/&#34;&gt;Semantic MediaWiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want to know exactly how I do that or what it looks like… you’ll have to wait on another post. (I’ve been keeping the wiki for nearly a decade and created a three-part series on how to set one up back in, probably, 2009 but that’s &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; gone.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So watch for those posts. Hopefully they can be of help to you. (Whenever they get here.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October Squad Ghouls Network Take-Over: Postmortem</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2018-11-01-october-squad-ghouls-network-take-over-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2018-11-01-october-squad-ghouls-network-take-over-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://ryanstraight.com/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Well, it wasn’t as scary as I thought it would be. It was also quieter than I’d expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the month of October I was tasked with running the social media for the Squad Goals Network, a collective of pure academic and collaborative brilliance, of which I am honored to be a part. And you know what? I had a pretty good time. That said, let’s talk about it a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My basic theme for the month was &lt;em&gt;fear&lt;/em&gt;. Partly because it encompassed Halloween and partly because I believe doing things that scare you is an integral part of growing as a fully-realized person. Speaking of which, over the month I came to realize a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;revelation-1-anticipation-is-always-scarier-than-immersion&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Revelation #1: Anticipation is always scarier than immersion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about something is always going to be more terrifying than actually being in the situation. I kept thinking, “Is it going to be good enough?” or “Will I make a fool of myself?” or “What if I don’t have anything to say?” Upon reflection, that last one was never a real concern; the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; concern was “What if I don’t have anything &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; to say?” But here’s the point: there was never any expectation that the things I posted or wrote would all need to be meticulously crafted, thoughtful, brilliant nuggets of wisdom. If you spend all your time crafting you never actually produce anything, after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;revelation-2-im-an-amplifier-not-a-bullhorn&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Revelation #2: I’m an amplifier, not a bullhorn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some people—my takeover predecessor Angela and successor Terry, just to name two—who are fantastic at creating and shouting amazing things. They make connections with new people incredibly easily and actively seek out those connections. I, on the other hand, found myself being more of an amplifier for other people. In terms of Twitter, it manifested in many, many retweets but very few unique, composed tweets. There’s no right or wrong way to do this, of course. Each person has their own style and priorities. Still, if I had to choose which I find more useful… it isn’t my version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;revelation-3-a-month-is-no-time-at-all&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Revelation #3: A month is &lt;strong&gt;no time at all&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, wow, did that go quickly. Though it’s probably compounded by my birthday being at the end of October and I was eager to have that over and done with. (Thirty seven is such a low-priority age, I feel.) Now that it’s November and I can get back into my regular routine it’s suddenly conference season and the holidays. There’s never enough time for &lt;em&gt;any of it&lt;/em&gt;. Life, I mean. Never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, thank you for putting up with me behind the wheel for a month. I’ll still be amplifying the voices of brilliance I’m surrounded by in this group and expect those that come after me to do even better (which, to be honest, ain’t hard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9x9x25 Challenge: The Harshest Mirror</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2018-10-16-9x9x25-challenge-the-harshest-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2018-10-16-9x9x25-challenge-the-harshest-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflection is hard. It can be scary. Not for lack of content but for the what it means to potentially confront your shortcomings. Yes, the goal is to improve but to do that you must admit where you are lacking. Of course, we can couch this in platitudes like, “It’s not that I’m &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; at it, just that… it’s an area for growth.” And this is most likely true. Doesn’t change the fact that you still have to admit that first part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, I think, is fairly typical in higher education, especially for faculty whose entire &lt;em&gt;raison d’être&lt;/em&gt; is centered around expertise. It can feel like admitting one needs improvement can be to admit one has failed in some capacity. We all make mistakes, no doubt. We all have more to learn, of course. But it’s easier to do that in solitude, safer to make self-reflections private and not do what feels like laying bare your faults and shortcomings in public. Perhaps we all want to be the duck, legs paddling frantically under the water, but looking calm and collected on the surface. I know I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve written on imposter syndrome and becoming (or at least playing at being) a public intellectual and thinker. I’m not sure it comes easily and naturally to most people. For those for whom it does, it seems so &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt;. They seem fearless and display the bright colors of poisonous animals that tells you, “I’m making myself vunerable to help others; attack at your own peril because you will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; like the outcome.” It’s something to which to aspire, don’t get me wrong. I &lt;strong&gt;wish&lt;/strong&gt; I had that sort of strength and fearlessness. As it happens… I don’t. At least, not yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to be able to say, “I don’t know” when a student asked a really fantastic or insightful question that I felt like I &lt;em&gt;should’ve&lt;/em&gt; been able to answer. Perhaps I did know the answer but couldn’t recall it at the moment. Perhaps I understood the questions wrong. Perhaps it was just something I flat-out did not know. Of course, we all do the redirect and say something like, “That’s a great question. How about we all do some research and see what we come up with?” That is the goal, after all: to get learners to become self-directed. Still, “That’s a great question” is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; the same as specifically saying, “I don’t know.” I’m still somewhat afraid of that. Remember, there’s a difference between being simply ignorant of something and being unprepared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is precisely why I chose “fear” as my SGN topic for the month and why I want to talk about it today: my goal is to overcome that particular fear this year. This month, if I can. Forget the New Year’s Resolution; we need the Halloween Overcoming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9x9x25 Challenge: An Introduction and a Plan</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2018-10-02-9x9x25-challenge-an-introduction-and-a-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2018-10-02-9x9x25-challenge-an-introduction-and-a-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start off with, let me say that I volunteered the &lt;a href=&#34;https://squadgoalsnetwork.com&#34;&gt;#SquadGoalsNetwork&lt;/a&gt; for this challenge and take full responsibility for it. That said, I’m looking for the entire squad to do the challenge in total, not for each member to do their own 9x9x25 challenge. They can if they want but it’s far from necessary. I’m hard but I’m not cruel, sheesh. The SGN is (and continues to grow into) a collection of incredibly talented and reflective people, so the content produced should be impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first, let’s look at what the &lt;strong&gt;9x9x25 Challenge&lt;/strong&gt; is. I was introduced to it via Twitter by our own &lt;a href=&#34;http://squadgoalsnetwork.com/2018/09/19/meet-the-authors-terry-greene/&#34;&gt;Terry Green&lt;/a&gt;. The challenge is “&lt;a href=&#34;https://extend-domains.ecampusontario.ca/the-9x9x25-challenge-more-but-not-all-the-details/&#34;&gt;to write about your teaching in 9 posts, over 9 weeks, with a minimum of 25 sentences per post&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my first reflection, I think it’s worth talking a bit about the details of my position: I teach entirely online at both the undergraduate and graduate levels at a very large Research-1 institution, and, while I’m at a giant R1, I’m what’s considered “career-track” faculty, which is to say I’m not tenure-track. My contract consists entirely of teaching and service requirements with no research expected (though, obviously, I still do it, which is the topic for another day). My normal schedule is 80% teaching (so 4 classes per semester, each counting as 20% of my time) and 20% service. This is pretty standard at our institution for career-track faculty, I believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching entirely online—and I mean entirely, not just hybrid or having an online section; the entire program is constructed and billed as being online—makes for an interesting cocktail of convenience, agility, and distance, for both good and bad. We can collaborate in our pajamas, we can make changes and implement them at moment’s notice, and reach students that couldn’t physically reach us otherwise. It’s pretty phenomenal in that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can get lonely, though. I go to great pains to build community with my students, within the program, and interdisciplinarily across the college and campus, but at the end of the day I’m still sitting in my home office, hitting keys to communicate. Sure, video conferencing has gotten considerably better over the past few years but, just as there’s an experiential difference between paper books and ebooks, it’s just not the same as sitting down in physical proximity with someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s this distance that actually caused me to accept the invitation to teach an Honors class on main campus every spring semester. But, I think I’ll leave that reflection topic for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of the 9x9x25 challenge is, in part, to encourage us to be more thoughtful and reflective about our teaching practices. The hope I have is that I will really begin focusing on this next week as that’s a “new semester” for us (a second 7.5-week session within a larger fall semester) and I can begin with a new class experience. I have a TA (kind of, we call it something different and there are other requirements but it’s easier to just say “TA”) and am looking forward to reflecting on how I orchestrate the inclusion of her knowledge and talent into the class. The class that’s beginning is hands-down my most popular class, which makes it &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; easier to be positive about reflections. (When students are excited and happy by default it leaves you with more energy to make improvements rather than feeling like you need to put out fires.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to reading others’ reflections as the challenge progresses!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2018 SGN Social Media Takeover</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2018-10-01-october-2018-sgn-social-media-takeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2018-10-01-october-2018-sgn-social-media-takeover/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://ryanstraight.com/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As such, I wanted to share a little bit about the concept, the process, the expectations, and the theme of the month. The sheer organization, thoughtfulness, and inclusion of last month’s takeover by &lt;a href=&#34;http://angelagunder.com/&#34;&gt;Angela Gunder&lt;/a&gt; means there are some pretty high standards for this month. That was in part the reason for this month’s theme: &lt;strong&gt;fear&lt;/strong&gt;. Fun theme, right? Right? I mean, I’ve even got one of the &lt;em&gt;Silent Hill&lt;/em&gt; game soundtracks on while I write this. I’m 100% committed to this theme, I’m tellin’ ya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why fear? Simple: we all experience it and we best overcome it with help from our support systems, and what is a network like SGN at its core if not a support system? We share thoughts to clarify them, we collaborate to produce ideas and results that we never could’ve achieved on our own (synergy, basically, but that word has been robbed of all impact over the years, I think), and we quite literally just ask each other for help sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I’m so glad to have been included in this network of brilliance (constellation, remember?) is that I’m usually pretty bad about connecting with people. I’m terrible with names, I’ll fall off the face of the planet for weeks or months at a time as I obsess with something new, and my memory is almost completely overrun with random facts in place of useful things like details about the people in my life. A group like SGN goes a long way to helping me either deal with, remedy, or overcome those shortfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of overcoming fear is admitting one’s shortcomings to begin with. While I often think of and paint myself as a non-standard kind of academic (hence &lt;em&gt;The New Professor&lt;/em&gt;, my podcast), I recognize that I’m far from perfect and have many, many realms of improvement I can (and should) venture into. For some, like myself, even admitting that can be scary. It’s not like it’s a secret; nobody’s perfect. It’s about acknowledging that imperfect as areas for growth, not permanent and irreparable flaws. I sometimes feel we think of ourselves as marble statues, hoping to put on display the most perfect version of ourselves: polished, impressive, towering. Then when we make mistakes or simply fail at something, that patina of perfection is marred in some way that we just know someone is going to notice and it will permanently alter and diminish the persona we’ve so carefully sculpted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I get older and learn more and more than I know less and less about the world, it occurs to me that we’re not made of marble at all. We’re simply clay. We can be remolded and repaired, improved on and changed. This also makes us vulnerable as the wrong person can come along and take a chunk out of you. That’s where having a network, whether it’s a personal learning network or a support network comes in (though, as I said, I’d venture to say they’re often one and the same): not only do your friends and family and colleagues help you repair that damage, whatever it may be, but they help you become a better version of yourself. And that’s what we should all be striving for, after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s what this month is all about, for me, at least: acknowledging our fears, admitting we all make mistakes and sometimes fail despite our best efforts, and understanding that &lt;em&gt;that’s okay&lt;/em&gt;. When students tell me they’re anxious about a defense, for example, I always say the same thing: that means you care. Fear can be a great motivator if you let it be, if you can accept it as a hurdle to overcome rather than a door being shut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month, I’d like you to share with me and the rest of the squad what you’re afraid of and, if we can, we can work on it together. Also, I make absolutely no apologies for the massive number of Halloween puns and jokes that I’ll be making this month. I’m a Halloween baby and it’s creeped into the very fabric of my being. So, join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sqdglsntwrk&#34;&gt;Squad Ghouls Network&lt;/a&gt; (see?) for a month of acknowledging, admitting, and overcoming your fears.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squad Goals network</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/project/squad-goals-network-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 09:47:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/project/squad-goals-network-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Squad Goals Network&lt;/strong&gt; is a collection of like-minded teachers, designers, and researchers that get together to gab, think of innovative ways to bring technology and collaboration into higher education and K-12, and just generally have a good time. We try to uphold and demonstrate our principles through support and collaborative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://squadgoalsnetwork.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Squad Goals Network&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Academic Workflow: Paperless Researching</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2013-12-01-electronic-academic-workflow-paperless-researching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/2013-12-01-electronic-academic-workflow-paperless-researching/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://ryanstraight.com/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: this is old. Very old. I’m no longer a graduate student though I do still teach my graduate students to use these tools or a variation thereof. -RS, Feb 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below I’ve highlighted some of the tools that I use to keep myself from going insane while finishing my degree. I call it the Electronic Academic Workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;mendeley&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mendeley.com/&#34;&gt;Mendeley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mendeley.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mendeley is free software used to collect, organize , and annotate research articles, books, and other references. The Microsoft Word plug-in allows you to include citations in the text of your writing and automatically create bibliographies based on only what is cited in the paper using the citation style of your choice. If a PDF is attached to a bibliographic entry in Mendeley, you can highlight, type on, and add notes to the file just as you would if it were printed out (but this way everything is searchable). Auto-import will bring in PDFs you save to your computer and fill in the appropriate database fields (authors, title, journal, etc.) automatically. The website has a collection of user groups that share papers and notes. It also backs up your collection to the cloud and has mobile apps for both Android (unofficially) and iPhone/iPad. Make sure to check with your school to see if you’re eligible to get the premium &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mendeley.com/mendeley-institutional-edition/&#34;&gt;Mendeley Institutional Edition&lt;/a&gt; for free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;citavi&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://citavi.com/&#34;&gt;Citavi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;citavi.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paid software to collect, organize, remark on, annotate, and cite research articles, books, etc. Does much of what Mendeley does but I prefer it more for the actual quotations and citations that I’m using in my papers. That is, Mendeley is where I do my active reading and note-taking, then I collect the quotes (both direct quotes and paraphrases) in Citavi to use in my papers. This just keeps things separate, which can be a good thing. If you have a text that isn’t scanned or available online (like a textbook), I suggest putting the bibliographic record in Mendeley just to keep it in your “library,” but breaking up the Citavi entries into chapters. Your organizational structure may vary, clearly. It also has a task system built in, but it isn’t quite as robust as LiquidPlanner or Asana. (Adding Citavi into the mix between Mendeley and Scrivener was an idea first, to my knowledge, posited by &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://static1.squarespace.com/static/562a77a2e4b0ebb30f3df59c/562a821be4b0a3172623d1a9/562a823ae4b0a3172623d79d/1445626426776/?format=original&#34;&gt;Mickey the BLOSSOMING-Fledgling Researcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;scrivener&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener.php&#34;&gt;Scrivener&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;scrivener.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paid software for organizing your writing. Built for fiction or non-fiction. Mainly for Mac but a Windows version was recently released. Extremely feature-filled and is great for organizing the myriad and disparate ideas that go into a large academic project. The only downside to Scrivener is that it is visually very busy. While it will help you organize all your writing, it can take quite some time to get used to working in the environment. Sticking with it is well worth the time and effort, however. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www2.palomar.edu/pages/kfalcone/2013/06/28/scrivenerapp-how-i-love-thee-my-dissertation-savior/&#34;&gt;Screenshot via Kelly Falcone&lt;/a&gt;. Her write-up is worth reading.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;liquidplanner&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.liquidplanner.com/signup_a/583/3b67a0fdecda3a0bee120c81c8dc149efcbd1162&#34;&gt;LiquidPlanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;liquidplanner.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free (for teachers and students) project tracking. Fantastic for visualizing and keeping track of how much effort and time is required for projects, from individual class projects or your entire degree. Has mobile applications and social/team capabilities. Really helps you peg down your timeline. Open an account with the free trial first, then visit here to upgrade to the free education-based license. (Title is an affiliate link.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;asana&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://asana.com/&#34;&gt;Asana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;asana.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free web service for tracking tasks. Has mobile applications and social/team capabilities. The interface is intuitive and attractive. It’s preferable, for me, for just those one-off to-dos. “Return library book” or “Water the garden,” that sort of thing. I leave this and LiquidPlanner as pinned tabs in Chrome. There is a social aspect to it if you’re working in teams that needs a to-do manager, but I can’t speak to how well it works as everything I do is solo. It’s more for just keeping the list of things rather than trying to organize and visualize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;evernote&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://evernote.com/&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[]evernote.jpeg)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free software and web service for collecting … anything, really. Think of it as an “everything bucket.” Evernote is my repository for everything that’s not a research paper. Whether it’s just an article that I want to keep track of, notes from a meeting at work, or copies of important emails to and from my committee, it all goes here. The web clipper will snag anything from any page and import it. Plays very nicely with IFTTT and can automate a great deal of your online presence. There’s no shortage of write-ups on Evernote. For just about anything you’d need, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/tag/evernote&#34;&gt;Lifehacker’s Evernote tag&lt;/a&gt;. (Image displayed is the web service.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;redlaser-now-defunct&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;RedLaser (Now defunct)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;redlaser.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;App for scanning barcodes. Can create lists of them, which makes it easy to import a large collection of books into services like GoodReads or Citavi. Not really part of my workflow, but nice to have around when I need it, especially when you’re in a bookstore or someone’s office and they have a book you want to remember to get. Alternatively, in that case, you could just take a picture of the cover as an Evernote note. Available for Android, iOS, and Windows phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;phraseexpresstextexpanderetc&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phraseexpress.com/&#34;&gt;PhraseExpress&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;http://smilesoftware.com/TextExpander/index.html&#34;&gt;TextExpander&lt;/a&gt;/Etc&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;phraseexpress.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text replacement software. For example, typing “mmr” could be set to replace an entire multivariate multiple regression SPSS syntax. I have a rather lengthy one set to “sig;” that inserts my full email signature, plus a random quote from a list of 200 or so. (Keeps the sig fresh, I feel.) Quicker than copying and pasting, and prevents user error. If you type something over and over and over then software like this becomes a huge boon and saves ridiculous amounts of time (not to mention the relief of knowing that if it’s right once, it’s right every time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, those are the main players that keep me going in a (relatively) smooth fashion. Need an APA citation real quick? Right-click the entry in Mendeley and copy as a citation. Need to find a quote but only remember a couple words? Citavi to the rescue. Unexpectedly got an extra couple hours free? LiquidPlanner shows me what I really need to be working on next. (This was originally posted on Medium.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
