<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading lists | ryan straight, ph.d</title>
    <link>https://ryanstraight.com/category/reading-lists/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ryanstraight.com/category/reading-lists/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Reading lists</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ryanstraight.com/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Reading lists</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/category/reading-lists/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources and readings: General cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/resources-and-readings-general-cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/resources-and-readings-general-cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://ryanstraight.com/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is a basic collection of general cybersecurity readings with an abstract/preview and very lazy APA formatting. I’ll be adding to this as time goes by and creating more specific reading lists, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Al-khateeb, S., Hussain, M. N., &amp;amp; Agarwal, N. (2017). Social Cyber Forensics Approach to Study Twitter’s and Blogs’ Influence on Propaganda Campaigns. In D. Lee, Y.-R. Lin, N. Osgood, &amp;amp; R. Thomson (Eds.), Social, Cultural, and Behavioral Modeling (Vol. 10354, pp. 108–113). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-60240-0_13&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-60240-0_13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s information technology age our political discourse is shrinking to ﬁt our smartphone screens. Online Deviant Groups (ODGs) use social media to coordinate cyber propaganda campaigns to achieve strategic and political goals, inﬂuence mass thinking, and steer behaviors. In this research, we study the ODGs who conducted cyber propaganda campaigns against NATO’s Trident Juncture Exercise 2015 (TRJE 2015) and how they used Twitter and blogs to drive the campaigns. Using a blended Social Network Analysis (SNA) and Social Cyber Forensics (SCF) approaches, “anti-NATO” narratives were identiﬁed on blogs. The narratives intensiﬁed as the TRJE 2015 approached. The most inﬂuential narrative identiﬁed by the proposed methodology called for civil disobedience and direct actions against TRJE 2015 speciﬁcally and NATO in general. We use SCF analysis to extract metadata associated with propaganda-riddled websites. The metadata helps in the collection of social and communication network information. By applying SNA on the data, we identify inﬂuential users and powerful groups (or, focal structures) coordinating the propaganda campaigns. Data for this research (including blogs and metadata) is accessible through our in-house developed Blogtrackers tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Al-Shaer, E., Wei, J., Hamlen, K. W., &amp;amp; Wang, C. (Eds.). (2019). Autonomous Cyber Deception: Reasoning, Adaptive Planning, and Evaluation of HoneyThings. Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-02110-8&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-02110-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why Cyber Deception? Cyberattacks have evolved to be highly evasive against traditional prevention and detection techniques, such as antivirus, perimeter firewalls, and intrusion detection systems. At least 360,000 new malicious files were detected every day, and one ransomware attack was reported every 40 s in 2017 (Chap. 10). An estimated 69% of breaches go undetected by victims but are spotted by an external party, and 66% of breaches remained undiscovered for more than 5 months (Chap. 10). Asymmetries between attacker and defender information and resources are often identified as root causes behind many of these alarming statistics. Cybercriminals frequently reconnoiter and probe victim defenses for days or years prior to mounting attacks, whereas defenders may only have minutes or seconds to respond to each newly emerging threat. Defenders seek to protect infrastructures consisting of thousands or millions of assets, whereas attackers can often leak sensitive information or conduct sabotage by penetrating just one critical asset. Finding ways to level these ubiquitous asymmetries has therefore become one of the central challenges of the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Is Cyber Deception? Cyber deception has emerged as an effective and complementary defense technique to overcome asymmetry challenges faced by traditional detection and prevention strategies. Approaches in this domain deliberately introduce misinformation or misleading functionality into cyberspace in order to trick adversaries in ways that render attacks ineffective or infeasible. These reciprocal asymmetries pose scalability problems for attackers similar to the ones traditionally faced by defenders, thereby leveling the battlefield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber Deception Models Cyber deception can be accomplished in two major ways: (1) mutation, to frequently change the ground truth (i.e., the real value) of cyber parameters such as cyber configuration, IP addresses, file names, and URLs, and (2) misrepresentation, to change or corrupt only the value returned of cyber parameters to the attacker without changing the ground truth such as false fingerprinting, files, and decoy services.We therefore call the cyber parameters used for deceiving the attackers HoneyThings. Using the concept of HoneyThings in both approaches expands the cyber exploration space for adversaries to launch effective attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brady, W. J., Wills, J. A., Burkart, D., Jost, J. T., &amp;amp; Van Bavel, J. J. (2019). An ideological asymmetry in the diffusion of moralized content on social media among political leaders. Journal of Experimental Psychology: General, 148(10), 1802–1813. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/xge0000532&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/xge0000532&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online social networks constitute a major platform for the exchange of moral and political ideas, and political elites increasingly rely on social media platforms to communicate directly with the public. However, little is known about the processes that render some political elites more influential than others when it comes to online communication. Here, we gauge influence of political elites on social media by examining how message factors (characteristics of the communication) interact with source factors (characteristics of elites) to impact the diffusion of elites’ messages through Twitter. We analyzed messages (N ϭ 286,255) sent from federal politicians (presidential candidates, members of the Senate and House of Representatives) in the year leading up to the 2016 U.S. presidential election—a period in which Democrats and Republicans sought to maximize their influence over potential voters. Across all types of elites, we found a “moral contagion” effect: elites’ use of moral-emotional language was robustly associated with increases in message diffusion. We also discovered an ideological asymmetry: conservative elites gained greater diffusion when using moral-emotional language compared to liberal elites, even when accounting for extremity of ideology and other source cues. Specific moral emotion expressions related to moral outrage—namely, moral anger and disgust—were impactful for elites across the political spectrum, whereas moral emotion expression related to religion and patriotism were more impactful for conservative elites. These findings help inform the scientific understanding of political propaganda in the digital age, and the antecedents of political polarization in American politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brady, W. J., Wills, J. A., Jost, J. T., Tucker, J. A., &amp;amp; Van Bavel, J. J. (2017). Emotion shapes the diffusion of moralized content in social networks. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 114(28), 7313–7318. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1618923114&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1618923114&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political debate concerning moralized issues is increasingly common in online social networks. However, moral psychology has yet to incorporate the study of social networks to investigate processes by which some moral ideas spread more rapidly or broadly than others. Here, we show that the expression of moral emotion is key for the spread of moral and political ideas in online social networks, a process we call “moral contagion.” Using a large sample of social media communications about three polarizing moral/political issues (n = 563,312), we observed that the presence of moral-emotional words in messages increased their diffusion by a factor of 20% for each additional word. Furthermore, we found that moral contagion was bounded by group membership; moral-emotional language increased diffusion more strongly within liberal and conservative networks, and less between them. Our results highlight the importance of emotion in the social transmission of moral ideas and also demonstrate the utility of social network methods for studying morality. These findings offer insights into how people are exposed to moral and political ideas through social networks, thus expanding models of social influence and group polarization as people become increasingly immersed in social media networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dutta, S., Chakraborty, T., &amp;amp; Das, D. (2019). How Did the Discussion Go: Discourse Act Classification in Social Media Conversations. In D. P &amp;amp; A. Jurek-Loughrey (Eds.), Linking and Mining Heterogeneous and Multi-view Data (pp. 137–160). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-01872-6_6&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-01872-6_6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last two decades, social media has emerged as almost an alternate world where people communicate with each other and express opinions about almost anything. This makes platforms like Facebook, Reddit, Twitter, Myspace, etc., a rich bank of heterogeneous data, primarily expressed via text but reflecting all textual and non-textual data that human interaction can produce. We propose a novel attention-based hierarchical LSTM model to classify discourse act sequences in social media conversations, aimed at mining data from online discussion using textual meanings beyond sentence level. The very uniqueness of the task is the complete categorization of possible pragmatic roles in informal textual discussions, contrary to extraction of question–answers, stance detection, or sarcasm identification which are very much role specific tasks. Early attempt was made on a Reddit discussion dataset. We train our model on the same data, and present test results on two different datasets, one from Reddit and one from Facebook. Our proposed model outperformed the previous one in terms of domain independence; without using platform-dependent structural features, our hierarchical LSTM with word relevance attention mechanism achieved F1-scores of 71% and 66%, respectively, to predict discourse roles of comments in Reddit and Facebook discussions. Efficiency of recurrent and convolutional architectures in order to learn discursive representation on the same task has been presented and analyzed, with different word and comment embedding schemes. Our attention mechanism enables us to inquire into relevance ordering of text segments according to their roles in discourse. We present a human annotator experiment to unveil important observations about modeling and data annotation. Equipped with our text-based discourse identification model, we inquire into how heterogeneous non-textual features like location, time, leaning of information, etc. play their roles in characterizing online discussions on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farkas, J., &amp;amp; Neumayer, C. (2020). Disguised Propaganda from Digital to Social Media. In J. Hunsinger, M. M. Allen, &amp;amp; L. Klastrup (Eds.), Second International Handbook of Internet Research (pp. 707–723). Springer Netherlands. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-024-1555-1_33&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-024-1555-1_33&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disguised propaganda and political deception in digital media have been studied since the early days of the World Wide Web. At the intersection of internet research and propaganda studies, this chapter explores disguised propaganda on websites and social media platforms. Based on a discussion of key concepts and terminology, this chapter outlines how new modes of deception and source obfuscation emerge in digital and social media environments, and how this development complicates existing conceptual and epistemological frameworks in propaganda studies. The chapter concludes by arguing that contemporary challenges of detecting and countering disguised propaganda can only be resolved, if social media companies are held accountable and provide the necessary support for user contestation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jajodia, S., Subrahmanian, V. S., Swarup, V., &amp;amp; Wang, C. (Eds.). (2016). Cyber Deception: Building the Scientific Foundation. Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-32699-3&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-32699-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This volume is designed to take a step toward establishing scientific foundations for cyber deception. Here we present a collection of the latest basic research results toward establishing such a foundation from several top researchers around the world. This volume includes papers that rigorously analyze many important aspects of cyber deception including the incorporation of effective cyber denial and deception for cyber defense, cyber deception tools and techniques, identification and detection of attacker cyber deception, quantification of deceptive cyber operations, deception strategies in wireless networks, positioning of honeypots, human factors, anonymity, and the attribution problem. Further, we have made an effort to not only sample different aspects of cyber deception, but also highlight a wide variety of scientific techniques that an be used to study these problems. It is our sincere hope that this volume inspires researchers to build upon the knowledge we present to further establish scientific foundations for cyber deception and ultimately bring about a more secure and reliable Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kwon, S., Cha, M., Jung, K., Chen, W., &amp;amp; Wang, Y. (2013). Prominent Features of Rumor Propagation in Online Social Media. 2013 IEEE 13th International Conference on Data Mining, 1103–1108. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1109/ICDM.2013.61&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1109/ICDM.2013.61&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem of identifying rumors is of practical importance especially in online social networks, since information can diffuse more rapidly and widely than the ofﬂine counterpart. In this paper, we identify characteristics of rumors by examining the following three aspects of diffusion: temporal, structural, and linguistic. For the temporal characteristics, we propose a new periodic time series model that considers daily and external shock cycles, where the model demonstrates that rumor likely have ﬂuctuations over time. We also identify key structural and linguistic differences in the spread of rumors and non-rumors. Our selected features classify rumors with high precision and recall in the range of 87% to 92%, that is higher than other states of the arts on rumor classiﬁcation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mazarr, M., Bauer, R., Casey, A., Heintz, S., &amp;amp; Matthews, L. (2019). The Emerging Risk of Virtual Societal Warfare: Social Manipulation in a Changing Information Environment. RAND Corporation. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7249/RR2714&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.7249/RR2714&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis is part of a larger study on techniques of social manipulation and was motivated by recent Russian efforts to manipulate Western information environments. This study focuses on the future of social manipulation efforts and involved a survey of multiple, overlapping information-related technologies and their potential for manipulation. It describes the emerging phenomenon of virtual societal warfare and suggests avenues for Western democracies to respond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Park, J., Mohaisen, A., Kamhoua, C. A., Weisman, M. J., Leslie, N. O., &amp;amp; Njilla, L. (2020). Cyber Deception in the Internet of Battlefield Things: Techniques, Instances, and Assessments. In I. You (Ed.), Information Security Applications (Vol. 11897, pp. 299–312). Springer International Publishing. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-39303-8_23&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-39303-8_23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Battleﬁeld Things (IoBT) is an emerging application to improve operational eﬀectiveness for military applications. The security of IoBT is one of the more challenging aspects, where adversaries can exploit vulnerabilities in IoBT software and deployment conditions to gain insight into their state. In this work, we look into the security of IoBT from the lens of cyber deception. First, we formulate the IoBT domain as a graph learning problem from an adversarial point of view and introduce various tools through which an adversary can learn the graph starting with partial prior knowledge. Second, we use this model to show that an adversary can learn high-level information from low-level graph structures, including the number of soldiers and their proximity. For that, we use a powerful n-gram based algorithm to obtain features from random walks on the underlying graph representation of IoBT. Third, we provide microscopic and macroscopic approaches that manipulate the underlying IoBT graph structure to introduce uncertainty in the adversary’s learning. Finally, we show our approach’s eﬀectiveness through analyses and evaluations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pond, P., &amp;amp; Lewis, J. (2019). Riots and Twitter: Connective politics, social media and framing discourses in the digital public sphere. Information, Communication &amp;amp; Society, 22(2), 213–231. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/1369118X.2017.1366539&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/1369118X.2017.1366539&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media technologies like Twitter are credited with enabling a new form of connective action, in which political movements coalesce and mobilise around hashtags, memes and personalised action frames. After the UK riots in 2011, citizen ‘broom armies’ took to the streets to clear up and repair damage. Different hashtags, including #RiotCleanUp and #OperationCupOfTea, were implicated in these movements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shu, K., Sliva, A., Wang, S., Tang, J., &amp;amp; Liu, H. (2017). Fake News Detection on Social Media: A Data Mining Perspective. 19(1), 22–36.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media for news consumption is a double-edged sword. On the one hand, its low cost, easy access, and rapid dissemination of information lead people to seek out and consume news from social media. On the other hand, it enables the wide spread of “fake news”, i.e., low quality news with intentionally false information. The extensive spread of fake news has the potential for extremely negative impacts on individuals and society. Therefore, fake news detection on social media has recently become an emerging research that is attracting tremendous attention. Fake news detection on social media presents unique characteristics and challenges that make existing detection algorithms from traditional news media ineﬀective or not applicable. First, fake news is intentionally written to mislead readers to believe false information, which makes it diﬃcult and nontrivial to detect based on news content; therefore, we need to include auxiliary information, such as user social engagements on social media, to help make a determination. Second, exploiting this auxiliary information is challenging in and of itself as users’ social engagements with fake news produce data that is big, incomplete, unstructured, and noisy. Because the issue of fake news detection on social media is both challenging and relevant, we conducted this survey to further facilitate research on the problem. In this survey, we present a comprehensive review of detecting fake news on social media, including fake news characterizations on psychology and social theories, existing algorithms from a data mining perspective, evaluation metrics and representative datasets. We also discuss related research areas, open problems, and future research directions for fake news detection on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tang, Z., &amp;amp; Liu, X. (2019). Research on the Status Quo and Countermeasures of the Discourse Power of Cyberspace Ideology in the New Era. Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Contemporary Education, Social Sciences and Ecological Studies (CESSES 2019). Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Contemporary Education, Social Sciences and Ecological Studies (CESSES 2019), Moscow, Russia. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2991/cesses-19.2019.191&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2991/cesses-19.2019.191&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideology of discourse in the new era of cyberspace presents new features such as diversification of discourse subjects, diversification of discourse carriers, and complexity of discourse content. Among them, the cyberspace ideology discourse power is also facing the impact of Western culture penetration, multiculturalism, and the pressure of Western discourse power. To further construct cyberspace ideology discourse power in the new era, it is necessary to adhere to Marxism as the ideological guidance, strengthen the discourse subject, guide the ability to play, expand the discourse carrier, enhance the influence of discourse, innovate the discourse content, improve the quality of discourse, and then highlight the international voice of cyberspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vartanova, I., Eriksson, K., &amp;amp; Strimling, P. (2019). Country-Independence of Moral Arguments and Moral Opinion Dynamics. SSRN Electronic Journal. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3463009&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.3463009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do opinion dynamics compare across different countries? The moral argument theory of opinion dynamics says that public opinion on moral issues should generally become more liberal, and the rate of change should vary across issues according to how the different issue positions connect with moral arguments that are acceptable to liberals. We conducted a cross-cultural test of this theory, using new measures of the connections between moral arguments and positions together with available opinion data on 98 issues in the United States, 108 issues in the United Kingdom, and 26 issues in Sweden. In each country the theory successfully predicted the pattern of long-term opinion trends. Moreover, on those issues that were covered both in the US and in the UK, argument measures and opinion trends were highly similar between the two countries. In sum, moral arguments seem to have a large explanatory power transcending different political cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warner-Søderholm, G., Bertsch, A., Sawe, E., Lee, D., Wolfe, T., Meyer, J., Engel, J., &amp;amp; Fatilua, U. N. (2018). Who trusts social media? Computers in Human Behavior, 81, 303–315. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chb.2017.12.026&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chb.2017.12.026&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust is the foundation of all communication, yet a profound question in business today is how can we psychologically understand trust behaviors in our new digital landscape? Earlier studies in internet and human behavior have shown a signiﬁcant connection between social media use and user personality (Hughes, Rowe, Batey, &amp;amp; Lee, 2012). Still, the connection between type of online user and their trust values is an under researched area. Today, millions of people globally read newsfeeds and information via their digital networks, but we do not know enough about human behavior related to which speciﬁc users of social media actually trust the news they read online. In this study we apply items from ﬁve different validated scales to measure trust to investigate to what degree a users’ perception of trust varies depending on their gender, age, or amount of time spent using social media. Using a convenience population sample (n ¼ 214) signiﬁcant differences in levels of trusting behavior were found across gender, age, social media newsfeed preferences and extent of social media use. The ﬁndings suggest that women and younger users have the highest expectations for integrity, trusting others and expecting others to show empathy and goodwill. Implications of the results are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Westaby, J. D., Pfaff, D. L., &amp;amp; Redding, N. (2014). Psychology and social networks: A dynamic network theory perspective. American Psychologist, 69(3), 269–284. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/a0036106&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/a0036106&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on social networks has grown exponentially in recent years. However, despite its relevance, the ﬁeld of psychology has been relatively slow to explain the underlying goal pursuit and resistance processes inﬂuencing social networks in the ﬁrst place. In this vein, this article aims to demonstrate how a dynamic network theory perspective explains the way in which social networks inﬂuence these processes and related outcomes, such as goal achievement, performance, learning, and emotional contagion at the interpersonal level of analysis. The theory integrates goal pursuit, motivation, and conﬂict conceptualizations from psychology with social network concepts from sociology and organizational science to provide a taxonomy of social network role behaviors, such as goal striving, system supporting, goal preventing, system negating, and observing. This theoretical perspective provides psychologists with new tools to map social networks (e.g., dynamic network charts), which can help inform the development of change interventions. Implications for social, industrial-organizational, and counseling psychology as well as conﬂict resolution are discussed, and new opportunities for research are highlighted, such as those related to dynamic network intelligence (also known as cognitive accuracy), levels of analysis, methodological/ethical issues, and the need to theoretically broaden the study of social networking and social media behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources and readings: Technoscience and postphenomenology</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/post/resources-and-readings-technoscience-and-postphenomenology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/post/resources-and-readings-technoscience-and-postphenomenology/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://ryanstraight.com/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The idea is to read (and keep track of) a paper a day in 2018. Sounds easy, right? We’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It stems from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23365papers&#34;&gt;#365papers hashtag&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter. I’m going with Brook’s rules, too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to try to read &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/365papers?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;#365papers&lt;/a&gt; this year.  My own rules: a chapter counts as a paper, a paper I&amp;#39;m peer-reviewing counts, and it doesn&amp;#39;t have to be one paper a day for 365 days, but rather on average.  I&amp;#39;ll keep track in this thread.  Suggestions for papers welcome!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Brook Danielle Lillehaugen (@blillehaugen) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blillehaugen/status/947898628839849984?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;January 1, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be keeping track of my list below. No notes or anything, just the citations (with abstracts when available) in the order they were read. I’m including book chapters as papers as I’ve a lot of edited volumes and monographs I want to get through as well as discrete articles. Everything’s in lazy APA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be warned: this page could get &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olesen, F. (2012). Scientific Objectivity and Postphenomenological Perception. &lt;em&gt;Foundations of Science, 17&lt;/em&gt;(4), 357–362. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10699-011-9241-z&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10699-011-9241-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don Ihde’s paper “Stretching the in-between: Embodiment and beyond” appears to me as a stimulating, topical text with a number of important arguments about human embodiment as a dynamic and epistemically relevant dimension to scientific knowledge production. But, indirectly, the text also raises some basic questions about how to describe the (current) scope of technoscientific knowledge, and the potentials of postphenomenology to deal with this complicated, multi-stable issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;van den Eede, Y. (2011). In Between Us: On the Transparency and opacity of technological mediation. &lt;em&gt;Foundations of Science, 16&lt;/em&gt;(2–3), 139–159. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10699-010-9190-y&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10699-010-9190-y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different theoretical approaches each highlight only certain aspects of technologically mediated human existence. Philosophical theories of technology focus on mediation, but not on inter-human component. Theories of mediated interaction do not consider being-with-each-other an sich. Relationship scholars do not theorize technological mediation. This article considers different theories of technology, in order to devise a general theory of technological mediation. Technological mediation by its very nature, however, is transparent. How to approach it then? VDE explores the notion of transparency as it comes to the fore in the different perspectives on technology. The transparency-opacity in these theories all involve changing perspectives: from tool to use/medium to message/form to content/figure and ground, where opacity of the one means transparency of the other, and vice versa. Then, he systematized this into a broad analysis of technological mediation. In use relations, the transparency and opacity emerge in the “neutral” (efficient, easy) usage of the tool/medium/content/platform. In context relations, the transparency and opacity concern the social and political context of the technology: the (invisible) ways by which technologies produce and perpetuate social injustices. Use for FOLoF: the face is not a technology, but nevertheless it conjures a similar dynamic of transparency and opacity (faciality: you look at a collection of features, and see a person. Whole versus parts - Gestalt experience?) Question: which is the “us” in the title? VDE seems to be talking about technological mediation in a broad sense (which also includes technological mediation of self-world), but also about technological mediation of social interaction. He does not make this very relevant distinction clear, however!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adams, C. A., &amp;amp; Thompson, T. L. (2011). Interviewing objects: including educational technologies as qualitative research participants. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Qualitative Studies in Education, 24&lt;/em&gt;(6), 733–750. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/09518398.2010.529849&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/09518398.2010.529849&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article argues the importance of including significant technologies-in-use as key qualitative research participants when studying today’s digitally enhanced learning environments. We gather a set of eight heuristics to assist qualitative researchers in “interviewing” technologies-in-use (or other relevant objects), drawing on concrete examples from our own qualitative research projects. Our discussion is informed by Actor-Network Theory and hermeneutic phenomenology, as well as by the literatures of techno-science, media ecology, and the philosophy of technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hasse, C. (2008). Postphenomenology: Learning cultural perception in science. &lt;em&gt;Human Studies, 31&lt;/em&gt;(1), 43–61. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10746-007-9075-4&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10746-007-9075-4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article I propose that a postphenomenological approach to science and technology can open new analytical understandings of how material artifacts, embodiment and social agency co-produce learned perceptions of objects. In particle physics, physicists work in huge groups of scientists from many cultural backgrounds. Communication to some extent depends on material hermeneutics of flowcharts, models and other visual presentations. As it appears in an examination of physicists‚Äô scrutiny of visual renderings of different parts of a detector, perceptions vary in relation to social and bodily experiences. Vision in physics has seemingly allowed an objective perception at a convenient distance of the body. This article challenges this view and proposes that the variations can be analysed as cultural at two echelons with the help of a postphenomenological approach combined with cultural psychological theory of artifacts. A third echelon presumably constitutes the phenomenological limit to culture in science. Even this last resort of subjectivity can be embraced by a postphenomenological approach. The process of culturalization in physics can be defined as a process of situating knowledge in a body whose continuous learning of micro-and macro perceptions makes scientific renderings unstable. Taken together postphenomenology, following the distinctions between body one and body two, and combined with cultural psychological learning theory, enables new insight into what constitutes culture in science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verbeek, P. P. (2008). Cyborg intentionality: Rethinking the phenomenology of human-technology relations. &lt;em&gt;Phenomenology and the Cognitive Sciences, 7&lt;/em&gt;(3), 387–395. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11097-008-9099-x&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11097-008-9099-x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article investigates the types of intentionality involved in humantechnology relations. It aims to augment Don Ihdes analysis of the relations between human beings and technological artifacts, by analyzing a number of concrete examples at the limits of Ihdes analysis. The article distinguishes and analyzes three types of cyborg intentionality, which all involve specific blends of the human and the technological. Technologically mediated intentionality occurs when human intentionality takes place through technological artifacts; hybrid intentionality occurs when the technological actually merges with the human; and composite intentionality is the addition of human intentionality and the intentionality of technological artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dreyfus, H. (2009). Heidegger on Gaining a Free Relation to Technology. In D. M. Kaplan (Ed.), Readings in the Philosophy of Technology (2nd ed., pp. 25–33). London: Rowman &amp;amp; Littlefield Publishers, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moran, D. (2000). &lt;em&gt;Introduction to Phenomenology&lt;/em&gt;. London: Routledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Preface) This book is an introduction to phenomenology, a movement which, in many ways, typifies the course of European philosophy in the twentieth century. Writing at the close of this era, the extent of this contribution can now be more clearly articulated, appreciated, and, inevitably, criticised. Phenomenology was announced by Edmund Husserl in 1900–1901 as a bold, radically new way of doing philosophy, an attempt to bring philosophy back from abstract metaphysical speculation wrapped up in pseudo-problems, in order to come into contact with the matters themselves, with concrete living experience. As Husserl originally envisaged it, phenomenology had much in common with William James’ radical empiricism, but more than anything else it was stimulated by Franz Brentano’s ground-breaking work in descriptive psychology, the a priori science of the acts and contents of consciousness. Somewhat later, Husserl came to realise the connection between his conception of phenomenology and Descartes’s project of providing a secure edifice for knowledge. Husserl eventually came to see that his own project had much in common with Neo-Kantianism, and thus his phenomenology became a form of transcendental idealism. But his studies of consciousness also led him to pursue investigations into our awareness of time, and history, which led to his development of the concept of the life-world, and to investigations of the evolution of culture reminiscent of Hegel’s phenomenology of spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kline, S. J. (1985). What is technology? &lt;em&gt;Bulletin of Science, Technology &amp;amp; Society, 1&lt;/em&gt;, 215–218.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Opening paragraphs) In the late 20th century, there is only one thing most people agree about concerning technology – it is important. It is discussed almost as much as the weather, and sometimes it seems, with as little effect. But what is ’technology?’ If we look with even a little care, we find this same word is being used to represent things, actions, processes, methods and systems. ’Technology’ is also used symbolically as an epithet, for important working procedures, and to represent progress. This much conflict within the usage of one of our central terms won’t do; it can lead only to chaos. Even more important, the current vague use of the word ’technology’ hides from view two central concepts,and a central pattern of human behavior that we must have to make sense of our views of many critical questions in the current world including how we understand innovation, how we can communicate across Snow’s culture gap, and how we understand the way in which we humans make our living on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blitz, M. (2014). Understanding Heidegger on Technology. &lt;em&gt;The New Atlantis, 41&lt;/em&gt;, 63–80.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Opening paragraph) Martin Heidegger (1889–1976) was perhaps the most divisive philosopher of the twentieth century. Many hold him to be the most original and important thinker of his era. Others spurn him as an obscurantist and a charlatan, while still others see his reprehensible affiliation with the Nazis as a reason to ignore or reject his thinking altogether. But Heidegger’s undoubted influence on contemporary philosophy and his unique insight into the place of technology in modern life make him a thinker worthy of careful study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ihde, D. (2011). Stretching the In-between: Embodiment and beyond. &lt;em&gt;Foundations of Science, 16&lt;/em&gt;(2–3), 109–118. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10699-010-9187-6&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10699-010-9187-6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s scientific imaging technologies are able to detect and image emissions and radiations from a much wider range of the electromagnetic spectrum than ever before. Such phenomena lie beyond the horizons of ordinary human perceptibility. I examine here the implications of such “translation mediations” for the production of scientific knowledge and show how human embodiment is implicit for all perceptual observational possibilities. The framework is that of a postphenomenology which is able to relate these new phenomena to human embodiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosenberger, R. (2016). Notes on a Nonfoundational Phenomenology of Technology. &lt;em&gt;Foundations of Science, 22&lt;/em&gt;(3), 1–24. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10699-015-9480-5&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s10699-015-9480-5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emerging school of thought called postphenomenology’’ offers a distinct understanding of the ways that people experience technology usage. This perspective combines insights from the philosophical tradition of phenomenology with commitments to the anti-essentialism and nonfoundationalism of American pragmatism. One of post-phenomenology’s central positions is that technologies always remain multistable,’’ i.e., subject to different uses and meanings. But I suggest that as this perspective matures, philosophical problems are emerging around the notion of multistability, what I call the problem of invariance’’ and the problem of grounding.’’ These problems point out things that remain unclear within the postphenomenological framework, such as how it handles structural claims regarding a technology’s various stabilities, and how it grounds its claims. How can postphenomenology make structural claims about technology and yet remain anti-essentializing? And on what epistemological basis does it ground its claims about human-technology relations? The paper concludes with a series of prescriptions that, if followed, enable postphenomenology to make edifying claims about technology, all while avoiding the problems of invariance and grounding, and maintaining its commitments to anti-essentialism and nonfoundationalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aagaard, J. (2016). Introducing postphenomenological research: a brief and selective sketch of phenomenological research methods. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Qualitative Studies in Education, 30&lt;/em&gt;(6), 519–533. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/09518398.2016.1263884&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/09518398.2016.1263884&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In time, phenomenology has become a viable approach to conducting qualitative studies in education. Popular and well-established methods include descriptive and hermeneutic phenomenology. Based on critiques of the essentialism and receptivity of these two methods, however, this article offers a third variation of empirical phenomenology: Postphenomenology. The article introduces postphenomenology, a philosophy of technology that highlights the importance of technological mediation of experience: Technologies transform our perceptions (amplify/reduce) and translate our actions (invite/inhibit). Based on this framework, two approaches to empirical fieldwork are suggested: In-depth exploration of the typical use of a given technology and critical comparison of multiple versions of a technology. It is argued that using postphenomenology as a research method helps researchers explore technological mediation, a vital and oft-neglected aspect of educational practice, but the method simultaneously entails epistemological commitments such as multistability, reflexivity, and posthumanism. The article concludes by discussing future challenges for the postphenomenological method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tripa thi, A. K. (2015). Postphenomenological investigations of technological experience. &lt;em&gt;AI and Society, 30&lt;/em&gt;(2), 199–205. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00146-014-0575-2&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00146-014-0575-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology is inextricably woven into the social and cultural fabric of different cultures. Tool use technologies, created and used by our pre-sapiens relatives, preceded us by more than a million years. There are no human cultures that are pre-technological. All humans have a material culture with complexly patterned praxes involving artifacts; we have only recently begun to appreciate the completely of even what may be called technologically mediated cultures. Technologies either magnify or amplify human experiences and can change the ways we live. This non-neutral, transformative power of humans enhanced by technologies is essential feature of the human–technology relations. Technologies are the extension of our bodies. The technological form of life is part and parcel of culture, just as culture in the human sense inevitably implies technologies. Every technology, as a word, has a signifier and a meaning. The signifier can be seen as the hardware of the technology, while the meaning can be conceived of as the uses and the functions that the technology performs. However, a technology, like many words, tends to be ambiguous, that is its meaning is mutable. As a consequence, in order to make sense, a technology calls for a cultural context where to be embedded. In this essay, I will demonstrate how this relationship can be articulated and their main theoretical implications for the study of new technologies give rise to ethics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tripathi, A. K. (2016). Culture of sedimentation in the human-technology interaction. &lt;em&gt;AI and Society, 31&lt;/em&gt;(2), 233–242. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00146-015-0581-z&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s00146-015-0581-z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New technologies inspire new interface paradigms. Promising utility of new interfaces continues attracting their modification. It is argued that in order for human users to share phenomenological experiences through multi- modal systems, they need to deal with embedded computers. This paper discusses the embodied nature of communication and a need for the development of a postphenomenology of technology, which plays a vital role in the material culture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Neal Irwin, S. (2016). &lt;em&gt;Digital Media: Human-Technology Connection&lt;/em&gt;. Boulder, CO: Lexington Books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Twelve chapters) Digital Media: Human-Technology Connection examines what it is like to be alive in today’s technologically textured world and showcases specific digital media technologies that make this kind of world possible. So much of human experience occurs through digital media that reflection on the process and proliferation of digital consumption has become necessary. This book takes on that task through an interdisciplinary array of sources including philosophy, media studies, film studies, media ecology, and philosophy of technology. When placed in the interpretive lenses of artifact, instrument, and tool, digital media can be studied in a uniquely different way that pushes the boundaries on production, distribution, and communication and alters the way humans and technology connect with each other and the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friis, J. K. B. O., &amp;amp; Crease, R. P. (Eds.). (2015). &lt;em&gt;Technoscience and Postphenomenology: The Manhattan Papers&lt;/em&gt;. London: Lexington Books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Seventeen chapters) Friis and Crease capture Postphenomenology, a new field that has attracted attention among scholars engaged in technology studies. Contributors to this edited collection seek to analyze, clarify, and develop postphenomenological language and concepts, expand the work of Don Ihde, the field’s founder, and scout into fields that Ihde never tackled. Many of the contributors to this collection had especially close ties to Ihde and have benefited from close work with him. This combined with the distinctive diversity of the contributors—18 people from 10 different countries—enables this volume to put on display the diversity of content and styles in this young movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
